JAMES RUTLEDGE

PHONE +1 512 423 8906 GITHUB github.com/jmz527

EMAIL jarutledge2@gmail.com

PERSONAL jamesaaronrutledge.com

LINKEDIN linkedin.com/in/jmz527

CHMMADV

I am a TDD friendly, full-stack web developer with over five years of experience. I resolve issues by arranging 1's and 0's in a meaningful sequence. I am an untapped source of homegrown, raw potential with a reservoir of patience to boot, and I believe the world deserves beautiful data structures.

EXPERIENCE

April 2015 – July 2015

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Software Engineer Student | Austin, TX

- 13 week full-time intensive program on full-stack web development.
- <u>TurnPlot</u>, a social platform with a virtual grid, provides a space for users to plant their web personas. Built with Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL.
- <u>PiqMapper</u>, a social tracking application, allows users to record their emotional well-being over time, using colors. Built with NodeJS and MongoDB.
- Collaborated with classmates on a restaurant reviews application, <u>App-e-tite</u>, built with Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL.

October 2010 – January 2013

MIND WINK

Co-Founder/Junior Web Developer | Austin, TX

- Designed and built websites and web applications
- Managed social media feeds and tracked user base
- Gained in-depth knowledge of WordPress and Drupal.
- Worked closely with clients to develop company brands.
- Lead pitch-meetings, developed presentations, established project management system and managed projects.

January 2008 – September 2010

FREELANCE

Front-End Web Developer | Austin, TX

- <u>EcoRise Youth Innovations</u>: Redesigned and maintained PHP website, pro bono.
- <u>The Hub Cyclery</u>: WordPress installation with a custom theme, designed and built.

EDUCATION

Graduated July 2015

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Development Immersive | Austin, TX

Graduated August 2014

University of Texas

B.A. English, Minor in Film | Austin, TX

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Ruby, JavaScript, SQL, SASS, HTML, CSS, XML, Bash

FRAMEWORKS + LIBRARIES Ruby on Rails, Node, jQuery, AJAX/JSON, Backbone, Sinatra, Bootstrap, Wordpress, Drupal

METHODOLOGIES

Agile, Object-Oriented Programming, MVC Design Patterns, Test-Driven Development

OTHER TOOLS

Git, GitHub, Heroku, Grunt, Bower, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, cPanel, Adobe Creative Suite, Chrome DevTools, QuickBooks

INTERESTS

- Web Development
- Filmmaking
- Travel
- Literature
- Cooking

FUN FACTS

- I have a working proficiency with Chinese & Spanish
- Last year I took a solo trip abroad, backpacking across Japan and South Korea
- My favorite fruit is mangosteen
- I can juggle